- [Narrator] This is the age of digital disruption.
Technology is transforming
the way businesses,
organisations and governments
engage with the world.
Organisations that least
expect it are finding
themselves becoming
'technology organisations'.
That's why it's so important
that we challenge each other
to work in a new way.
A way that is quick to respond
when circumstances change
and adapt when we learn new things.
For some of us, it will be a welcome shift
to an approach we know works.
For others it will be foreign.
And like anything new,
it might feel scary and uncomfortable,
but it is absolutely worth doing
and many organisations are
already seeing the progress
that new ways of working brings.
Following the Digital Service
Standard means you'll be sure
to be building the right thing.
The thing that meets users' needs.
Until now, government has
built services in a linear way
with delivery at the end
of a project timeframe.
We follow the plan, over
many months or years,
only to be smacked in the face by reality.
The thing we've spent
so long building doesn't meet users' needs
because we never found
out what those needs were.
Our new way of building is different.
Using an agile delivery
approach, we spend time learning
about users' needs first
so we can be sure to
design the right thing.
- Agility and the ways of working
that the Service Standard
brings to life aren't new.
These are great ways of working
that are recognised globally.
There's movements
happening across the globe
and in different areas and
in different industries,
so private sector we're
seeing amazing stuff
that the different
organisations are doing there
from an agility point of view,
and there's definitely an
opportunity for the government
and public sector to
leverage those as well.
- [Narrator] Working in iterative
cycles, we build quickly,
test what we've built
and evolve our work based
on constant measuring and testing.
By putting our concepts and prototypes
in front of real users,
we can adapt and refine
as we observe their behaviours.
- One of the teams I assessed
in the childcare space,
they were out there testing
the childcare centre
in the morning, making changes
at lunch, and back out there
in the afternoon for the kids' pick-up.
- [Narrator] Adaptability depends on flexibility.
You'll see in the Standard
that we have moved to
multidisciplinary teams,
which have all the specialist
skills to research, design,
build, operate, and measure the service.
We often say the unit
of delivery is the team.
What's great about the
multidisciplinary team is
that it has a flexible structure.
It changes and adapts at
various stages of the process.
The flexible structure
applies to the environment
that supports our
multidisciplinary teams, too.
Agile working environments are designed
to support maximum collaboration,
which means breaking
down physical barriers
and hacking the workspace,
because teams need easy ways
to coordinate their activities,
communicate progress, and collaborate.
But to make adaptability possible,
we need to build services
that allow us to change.
We need flexibility of technology.
So, when you're deciding
on the infrastructure
you're gonna work with,
it's important to make
choices that enable you
to change your mind at a later stage,
adapting your technology
and all of its components
as your understanding of how
to meet your user needs changes.
We can respond quickly to what we learn
and make changes seamlessly.
What's really important
is that our decisions
to change and adapt are driven by data.
Data drives decision-making,
not hunches or guesswork.
And preference doesn't get a vote.
We focus on what works, not what's liked.
We constantly gather data as we measure
how well our service
is working with users.
That means measuring how
well the system is performing
and how people are interacting
with it in real time.
As well as all our qualitative insights,
we use data analytics to help us
in developing and refining the service.
They should be built-in,
always on and easy to read.
They're an essential tool.
- How we can start making some
of those data-driven
decisions around what we do
in our service, so not just
reporting on the things
that we wanna see or that
we're currently interested
in this month, but actually
taking a user-centered approach
to everything that we're doing
and putting the user really
at the heart of even these metrics.
I mean we do it with the
service transformation.
We're putting it at the
heart of our dashboard
and the metrics we have, just
to understand their behaviours
and what they're doing, will really help
to continue building that
empathy that we kind of encourage
throughout the whole journey
of service transformation.
- [Narrator] The agile mindset is one of adaptability.
We diverge and converge.
Expand and contract.
We know we're asking you
to think differently.
It's change.
And change can be uncomfortable,
but it's worth it,
because this is our opportunity
to build the right thing in the right way
and make a real difference
to people's lives.
And we're here to support
you along the way.