- [Narrator] Design has the potential
to transform our world.
Its purpose is to help us do things.
So when design is good,
it becomes invisible.
It's a bit like air conditioning:
you don't even notice it's
there until it stops working.
- I don't think users even notice
good content and they shouldn't.
They should never even notice it
and I think that's when we know
we've done our job really well,
is when it just works
and there's no problems.
I think we notice bad
content straight away.
- [Narrator] Good design
also keeps people safe.
It works hard to protect privacy
and security, and that builds trust.
The best way to achieve
good design is to put people
at the centre of the process,
right from the start.
This is called user-centered design,
and it's the heart of the
Digital Service Standard.
So how does our user-centered
service design work?
First of all, let's just be clear.
Service doesn't mean website.
A service helps people do something.
The website is simply the layer
that people interact with.
A successful user-centered design
process challenges assumptions.
It spends time getting to know
the users to define the problem,
before even thinking about the solution.
Because when we really get
to know the motivations
of our users in their context,
we are better able to design
a service that will meet their needs.
It's important to think about the whole
user journey, and then
identify which point
in that journey you're designing for.
For example, finding
out if you're eligible
to become a childminder is different
to gathering documents so you can apply.
We have to look at the whole
picture, the whole ecosystem,
and how all the parts come
together for our users.
We design with the whole
end-to-end service in mind.
The Standard guides us in a new approach
that allows us to deliver
solutions to users quickly.
So when designing, we don't
tackle the whole thing in one go.
We begin with a thin slice,
starting small to produce
something that people can
use as fast as possible.
This involves making prototypes
based on our research
into the user's needs.
We should prototype lots of
different ideas and approaches.
Our prototypes start as low-fidelity
paper drawings, wireframes or similar.
This way we can explore as
many options as we need to,
with the knowledge that it's much
less expensive to make mistakes on paper.
Then we test them with real people,
measuring and gathering data
to inform the next iteration.
Once our tests with real users tell us
we've got some ideas that might
succeed, we start to develop
those designs in code, that
is HTML working copies.
Exploring a range of ideas
and alternatives with users
is faster and much less expensive.
It's a vital part of the design process.
Iterating like this makes
big failures unlikely
and turns small failures into lessons.
If an idea or a prototype isn't working
when you put it in front of your users,
don't be afraid to scrap
it and start again.
Understanding which ideas
and prototypes don't work
is an important way to learn quickly.
- I mean, fail, F-A-I-L, means
First Attempt In Learning.
That's what the acronym means.
So, failure is useful if we learn
something from it and
it's good to fail early.
If we spend a billion
dollars on a big IT system,
we have a huge risk because we have picked
one option out of a million options,
and we have followed that to
the end, the bitter end often.
And then when we face the music,
it is often the right solution
to the wrong question at best.
- [Narrator] So have courage.
Feel empowered to try, fail and try again.
Good design takes multiple
viewpoints into account.
This is why the Standard specifies
that you work in multidisciplinary teams,
to bring together different
perspectives, mindsets,
biases and complementary skills
from the very start of the service design.
Everyone on your team has a role to play
in the design of your service.
Their unique perspectives might identify
solutions no one else can see.
Collaboration leads to better designs,
which is why we're careful not to get
stuck in silos of our own making.
We talk to people, look
at other teams' walls,
ask questions, seek help, seek feedback.
We share our ideas and our
failures early, explore them,
build on what works,
and adopt them together.
And of course, the service should be
designed so that everyone can use it.
Most importantly, digital transformation
isn't just service design,
it's organisation design.
It's as much about people as it
is about pixels and processes.
- We don't want to be working in a world
where we're constantly scrambling
just to make ends meet.
We want to be able to do it in a way
that we understand why
we're all doing things.
We can collectively as an
organisation make better choices
about priorities if we're better aligned.
And the alignment around
our user-centered design,
we're aligned around
not an idea of saying, "What do you need?
"Okay, I'll build it for you."
What's your problem?
How can we solve it together?
- [Narrator] In government,
we are designing
something that people have to use.
Unlike with the private sector,
they don't have a choice.
A good design process allows
us to balance the outcomes
that government are looking
for with the needs of users.
When the balance is right and our users'
needs are met, everyone benefits.