We have the opportunity with technology
to provide far better services
than we have in the past
Then making it easy is the key.
- Often people with a
disability have to interact
with Government departments a lot
and a general way of getting
someone to fill in a form
is to send it out in the mail.
Well, it just doesn't work
for people who are paralysed.
- If you don't have the language skills
or the technical skills
in terms of being able
to use the system in the way it's
previously been designed,
it can make you frustrated.
- Users shouldn't have to understand
Government to deal with Government.
- People have no choice with Government,
so we have this deep moral
obligation to make sure
that what we're doing in
Government everybody can use.
- The citizen, they've got
to get on with their life.
So they want whatever they have
to do with Government to be easy.
- The important thing for us is
to focus on the opportunities.
They are very significant here.
Reinventing Government
and at the heart of that
it means a different
way of doing government.
- We looked all around the world
between the private sector,
the public sector and we said,
"What is best practise in
service design and delivery?"
So the Standard is a set
of principles, if you like,
around how we will design
and deliver services.
- Those core principles of building
yourself around the user.
- A set of really pragmatic
guidelines that are grounded
in experience and starts with user first.
- Users, design,
simplicity, adaptability.
If we design with users
in mind the whole time,
be they an end user, a
user within the ecosystem
of a service, then we get a
service that we know will work.
- We do need to take the
time to think through
how we can make things
simpler and clearer for them.
- That's what working in a
digital world is gonna be.
We have to be mindful
that life will move on.
We have to change our minds.
- It's about transforming
people and how we work.
It's not about technology.
It is not the bricks.
It is the mortar that matters.
- No one likes to change.
Let's be honest.
It's hard because it means
getting out of your comfort zone.
It means looking at
problems in a different way.
And it means listening to answers
that you don't want to hear.
- We already have runs on the board.
We actually need to remember that.
- You can stand around and
wait for someone else to do it,
but part of your role
in the Public Service
is to stand up and say, "Well,
now, we're gonna do this,
and this is how we're gonna do it."
- If Australians interact with
government, and at the end
of each of those interactions,
they say, "That was easy,"
I think we've had a huge impact.