- [Narrator] Simple isn't the first word that springs
to mind when describing government.
Interacting with us can be complex.
We're here to change that.
Using a government service
shouldn't be stressful,
confusing, or daunting.
It's our job to build services
that are simple enough
that people can do what they
need to do the first time,
without having to ask for help.
- I think frustration comes in a lot
of different forms for people,
because people have different
expectations about services.
And I think, quite often, their
expectations are really low
for government services.
So being frustrated can be
simply closing the computer
and saying, "Oh it's me.”
"I didn't know how to do that.”
"I'll just try again later."
And they see themselves as the
failure in that experience.
But as a trained researcher, you can start
to see that's not their fault at all,
and that's something probably
quite small we haven't
managed to communicate.
- [Narrator] It should also be simple
to build government services.
We make it simple by reusing
what others have already built,
so we can do less and focus
more on what our users need.
Creating a digital service isn't
just digitising a paper
form or extracting bits
of policy and sticking
them up on a website.
Often we need to re-think
the whole experience,
simplifying things so that people can do
what they need to do quickly and easily.
We need to be constantly
checking that things just work
for users, a wide range of users,
trying different things until they do.
It's about figuring out
which tool will get the
job done and using it.
When we design with simplicity,
people get what they need
to do and how they need to do it.
By reusing patterns,
we give users a consistent
experience no matter
which agency they're dealing with
or what device they're using.
That goes for those who use our
services every now and then,
and those who use them more frequently.
Keeping everything as simple
as possible is also more cost-effective.
Using common platforms
and systems means we build
or buy the technology once,
and reuse it many times across agencies.
We write open-source code
so that it can be shared
and reused by others.
And we make this simple
by being open by default,
so that others can
learn from our solutions
and expand upon them, contributing
back to the community.
Sharing saves time and it saves money.
You only have to look at
our Digital Marketplace,
released five months ahead of
schedule because we were able
to reuse open source code
from the U.K.'s Digital Marketplace.
And now Digital Marketplace
U.K. is incorporating one
of our new features, our
digital working order,
into their service.
So you can see, it's win-win.
Best of all, whenever
someone makes an improvement
to the code, everyone benefits.
And of course, content
and the language we use
must be simple, too.
We should do less, wherever possible.
If we put fewer questions
in the form, less clutter
in the interface, fewer
steps in the process,
we help to make it simpler.
- Simple and clear is
about the language we use
and the way we present the product,
the service that we're
designing to go digital.
Can people actually understand
what it is they're expected to do?
As public servants, we
tend to write, typically,
at a university level, because most
of us have got university
degrees of one sort or another.
That isn't our audience.
That isn't the general public.
We need to be presenting our services
in a language people can understand
and that the process
that we're taking them
through is clear and
straightforward for them.
- [Narrator] But we also need to acknowledge
that making something simple is hard work,
especially when it involves
complex information and systems.
The best way to achieve simplicity is
through a process of iteration.
That is, we try something,
we learn from it, and
we try something else.
It's the build, learn, measure cycle.
It takes a lot of time, but
we need to do the hard work
to make it simple for our users.
It's challenging, but
it's worth the effort.
And you can start today
by asking yourself,
how might we make everything we write,
even inside government, as
simple and clear as possible?