- [Narrator] We all have
to use government services.
So, to give our users
a government experience that's
fit for the 21st century,
we need to make sure
that interacting with us
is easy and efficient.
To help us do this,
we're introducing a new approach,
underpinned by a set of principles
called the Digital Service Standard.
It's grounded in user-centered design
and puts humans,
the people who use and
deliver our services,
at the centre of everything we do.
The first step
is to really get to
know who your users are
and their context.
And when we say users, we mean all users.
- Like looking out a million
windows all over the country
and seeing the world around you
and everybody that you walk past is a user
with their own story, their own history
that makes their experience
of dealing with government unique.
Our colleagues in government
are users of the overall service as well.
And helping make their
experience and their tools better
can be the most effective way
to improving end-users' experience too.
- [Narrator] You should spend
time learning about people
in the context that they use your service.
What's really happening?
Find out what they're doing now
to solve the problem you're working on.
Where are the pain points?
What are their common needs?
Flex your empathy muscle.
It's the most important tool you have.
When we do our early research,
we're not looking for evidence
to validate our project's existence,
or something that we've already announced.
We're looking for nothing more
than a rich understanding
of how are users are.
We need to expand our thinking
way beyond the borders of The Department.
It's about being curious,
keeping an open mind,
and trying to avoid unconscious biases.
We asked some user researchers
how it feels to learn
from users in this way.
- If you sit someone down,
and you ask them to go through a screen
and try and select their birthday,
and if you can watch them,
and you can see their
struggle because it's some
type of calendar
or something that they
just don't understand,
that's so much more powerful than saying
people struggle with
inputting their birthdate.
Seeing someone and how they struggle
really drives it home
that actually, our
assumptions may not be right
because we aren't the user.
- [Narrator] And the great news
is that starting with users
is more efficient,
because we know that the
service we build for them
will work right for them, the first time.
Nobody wants the
government to waste money.
It's our tax dollars after all.
Because when a user's
needs aren't met online,
they make mistakes that
need to be corrected,
they fail to comply with
what's required of them,
or they move to another more
costly, time-consuming channel.
An experience that's frustrating
and difficult for users,
and complicated and costly for government.
When you start with user needs,
you actually design something
they can use and understand straight away.
They can do what they need
to do quickly and easily
and move on.
This means a better and
cheaper service for everyone,
because people will choose
to use the digital service.
To get to know your users,
start with their stories.
Every user has one.
Of course, data is important too.
We build in layers of learning
by combining statistical data
with our qualitative research.
Here's how we do that.
- You can start to build a
story of their mental model
and start to understand
what they're thinking
when they go through the screens,
and why they're getting stuck,
and if they're getting
stuck at that point,
why continue?
Let's actually take that prototype back
and fix what's going wrong.
And we repeat that for
lots of different users,
and lots of different people
in lots of different locations.
- [Narrator] But you don't
only start with users.
You keep going.
We stay connected from our early research
right through development and beyond.
We keep asking, testing,
validating and measuring.
This is how we avoid
building false assumptions
into our services,
and learn whether our
design is doing its job,
and what we need to do
to keep making it better.
And when everyone in the
team understands their users,
they can all make smarter
decisions, quicker.
- One staff said to our client,
"I don't understand what you're saying.”
"Don't speak military to me.”
"Explain it in plain English."
To this guy,
all he's every known is military.
From the age of 17, his
father was in the military,
his mother was in the military.
That's the language he knows.
If he's going to tell
you about his service,
he's got answers to your questions,
that's the only way he knows
how to explain it to you.
That touched me when
he told me that story,
because I thought, well,
how can we say that to someone
when that's their life?
- [Narrator] What's also great
is that understanding user needs
is not one person's job.
It's a team sport.
It's everybody's job.
Understanding user needs is vital
for every single one of us, every time.
A user-centered approach
doesn't have to wait until
you're designing a service.
You can be actively empathetic
in the smallest things you do,
and you'll notice your actions
are much more effective.
So how could you bring
a little more empathy
into your day starting right now?
Start by thinking about
how you can find out what your users need.
What is working well, or not so well,
for them right now?
Most importantly,
we now have an opportunity
to really make a difference
to people's lives.
- I think it's a pretty natural
thing that most of us feel is
that if we can help others,
we feel satisfied ourselves.
I think that's where it all sort of stems from.