- [Narrator] The world is changing fast.
Despite our best intentions,
many government services
are being left behind.
To make government fit
for the 21st century,
we're introducing a new
and better way of working
and the Digital Service
Standard will be your guide.
So here is the Digital Service
Standard in Plain English.
Here's some people.
Jack, Jill, Me, you, my mom, your dad,
the guy who makes you
coffee in the morning,
your GP and his grandad.
All of them use government services
because to get things done,
we need to use government services.
If they want a holiday in Europe,
they'll need to get a passport and so on.
For some of them, it's easy.
For others, it's not so easy.
Some services are transactional.
Others just give you
information to help you
make decisions about things.
All of them use some IT.
We want them to become more
digital because they're
simple, clear, and fast, and it's cheaper.
Services are delivered
by government agencies,
that's us, using bits of technology,
usually provided by big suppliers
through long-term contracts.
It's expensive, it's hard to change,
and usually, it's not that great.
This is what people tell us all the time.
It needs to change and the
way we're gonna change it
is to make new technology
services delivered
over the internet, but we
won't be going it alone.
We'll be doing it together, guided by the
Digital Service Standard.
Let's break it down.
A service is made up of people,
process, and technology.
When our starting point is people,
my mom, the guy who makes you coffee,
and understanding what
they're trying to do
in their busy lives.
We can make a better service
and we can do it faster
if we, that's us in government,
have all the right people
with the right skills
making the service together,
continually checking in with users.
This way, we know we're
making the right thing.
Then we come to the process part.
We spend time learning what
people need then ask ourselves,
how might we meet that need?
We build some prototypes
and we ask people,
my mom and the guy who makes
you coffee, to try them out.
We learn from how people
use our prototypes
and then we build what works best
and start operating the service.
And that brings us to the
exciting part, the technology.
Let's make it simple.
Our services are made up of layers.
The first layer is where
people interact with us
via a paper form, a
telephone call, or commonly,
a website or app.
We present information
to people on this layer.
If we use words that people
understand, they'll get it.
We also need to make sure
people can access our services
and that they don't have
to tell us the same things
over and over, making it easier for people
to get things done.
The next layer is where all
the service-y things go.
These can be service specific
things like calculating tax,
or it might be something that
is used across many services
like making a payment, verifying identity,
or making sure things
are kept safe and secure.
Or they could be machinery kind of things
like sophisticated IT services, databases,
storage, mainframes, etc.
And as everything become more digital,
we become able to build
services in a modular way
using modular parts
that can be swapped out
without effecting other
parts and if we need to,
we can buy different parts
from different suppliers
instead of all of it from just one or two.
As we go through each of our
services, untangling them,
we'll know what all the common parts are
and then we can borrow
those parts from each other,
improving them as we need,
or just reusing them.
They cost a lot so we
don't want to keep on
buying the same parts every
time we have the same need.
By sharing parts, we
don't have to build things
from scratch every time.
This way, we save more
money and we can make
new services better, cheaper, and faster.
Oh, just one more thing.
Making our new services
in this way is a big job.
We've got lots of services and
lots of people who use them.
If we can stay on top of what's
happening for those people
and respond to their needs quickly,
then people will have more trust
in what we do here in government.
So as you build new services,
make sure you tell people, yep,
my mom and the coffee guy,
you've made a new service.
Invite them to try it out
and make sure you give them
an easy way to let you know
if it does the job for them.
That way, you'll be sure
to know what's working
and what's not, so you can
continue to make it even better,
and pretty soon, more
and more people will use
the new services because
they're simple, clear, and fast.
And that friends is the
Digital Service Standard
in Plain English.
Try it out and be sure to
let us know how you go.